<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Rafal Hollins</title><link>https://rhollins.github.io/content/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Rafal Hollins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 18:31:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rhollins.github.io/content/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jenkins on Azure Kubernetes Cluster (AKS) - How to recover Jenkins controller from Azure availability zone or region failure</title><link>https://rhollins.github.io/content/posts/jenkins-on-azure-kubernetes-cluster-aks-testing-disaster-recovery-between-availability-zones-and-regions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 18:31:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhollins.github.io/content/posts/jenkins-on-azure-kubernetes-cluster-aks-testing-disaster-recovery-between-availability-zones-and-regions/</guid><description>Jenkins is still a very popular CI/CD tool used by a lot of companies if you want to run it in Azure there are some usual options to choose from including stand alone VM&amp;rsquo;s or Azure Virtual Machine Scale Sets, but in this article, we will use AKS for both Jenkins controller and agents.
When deploying any solution there are a lot of things to consider like for example security, maintenance overhead, and cost but also reliability, and this last one is what we will focus on, in particular, we will try to answer the question: How to recover Jenkins controller from Azure zone and region failure.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Conditional Forwarding from On-Premise Domain Controller DNS with Azure DNS Private Resolver and AKS</title><link>https://rhollins.github.io/content/posts/configuring-conditional-forwarding-from-on-premise-domain-controller-dns-with-azure-dns-private-resolver-and-aks/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 18:31:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rhollins.github.io/content/posts/configuring-conditional-forwarding-from-on-premise-domain-controller-dns-with-azure-dns-private-resolver-and-aks/</guid><description>In this article, we will see how to resolve names of the K8s services running in AKS (Azure Kubernetes Service) from an on-premise desktop or server which is using DNS server running as part Active Directory Domain Controller. The assumption is that the company has a private connection with Azure using offerings like Expressroute.
We will also make use of Azure DNS Private Resolver which is quite a new PAAS solution and also allow us to use Conditional Forwarding from on-premise DC where before we would have to use some other target DNS server like for example custom CoreDNS deployed with etcd as backend in K8s which would be propagated by External DNS.</description></item></channel></rss>